#大家好 你看 現在這些小狗 長那麼大了
Hi everyone! Look! The puppies, they're that big now.
#都被我關在這裡
I lock them up all here.
#不面老是跑到外面去 跑到馬路中間去
Otherwise, they're just fooling around all day. They even run to the middle of the road.
#跳起來
Jump!
#你看 會跳的哦
Look! It can jump.
#跳起來
Jump!
#哇 那麼重啊
Wa! It's so heavy!
#現在又快三斤了哦
It weighs more than a kilogram now.
#現在我給它飯給它們吃
I feed them with rice these days.
#吃飯吃得飽一點
They feel more stuffed with rice.
#小黑狗
Black puppy!
#誒 這小花
Eh, this colourful puppy,
#很乖的哦
is really nice.
#你看 這個
Look! This is,
#這個 這個最調皮這個
this is, this is the naughtiest.
#看到我都怕 過來
It's so scared of me. Come here!
#好長哦這個 好長條
It's really long. This is, so long.
#這個是最長條的這個
This is the longest puppy.
#差不多有三斤半啦這個
It's almost 2 kilograms.
#跟竹鼠那麼胖啦你
You know, you're as fat as a bamboo rat.
#睡覺 別動
Sleep! Don't move!
#這個最大 這個
This is the largest.
#這隻是小黃狗
This is a brown puppy.
#快點吃
Eat more!
#好吃的 你不吃是不是
It's tasty! You're not eating, are you?
#你不吃等一下餓肚子的哦
You'll get hungry later if you don't eat know.
#沒有骨頭吃哦
You won't have any bones.
#現在豬肉那麼貴
Pork is so expensive these days.
#我買不起豬肉哦
I can't afford pork anymore.
#把它們放到下面去玩一下
Let me bring them down stair to have some fun.
#給它們活動活動筋骨
Let them move and stretch the muscles.
#打你哦
Beat you!
#這條好兇
This is fierce.
#你看小黑
Look at Blacky!
#現在很 最調皮就是它了
She's now very, she's the naughtiest,
#老是跳來跳去
always jumping around.
#不次拿鞭子來鞭一下它
Next time I'll flog her with a cane.
#一說拿鞭子鞭它它就跑啦
She runs away when I say I'll flog her.
#它肯定聽懂我說話
She certainly understands my words.
#你看這小狗 它會兩個腳走路的哦
Look at this puppy. It can walk on two legs.
#小豬 過來哦
Piggy! Come here!
#小豬
Piggy!
#過來
Come here!
#小狗很想你啦
The puppies miss you so much!
#要跟你玩 快點過來
They wanna play with you. Come on! Come here!
#不過來 不過來我就過去
You aren't coming. Then I come to you.
#小狗
Puppy!
#跟它玩
Play with it!
#去 找它玩
Go! Play with it!
#去 這還有一條 去 找它玩
Go! Here's one more puppy. Go! Play with it!
#豬看到都怕 看到這小狗都怕
The pig is scared of the puppies. It doesn't even want to see them.
#跑啦
It runs away.
#這小狗在拉繩子
The puppies are pulling the string.
#像蹦迪一樣
It's like disco.
一蹦一蹦的
Hop, hop, hop
#這是狗媽媽
This is the mommy.
#你們都那麼大了 遇有好意思
You are no longer a kid. Don't you feel ashamed?
#還好意思在蹭蹭蹭 你看 狗
You're still rub and rub and rub, you see? The dog...
#這狗媽媽最乖了
The mommy is the always the best.
#我從來不打它
I've never beaten her.
#其它的不聽話我就用這個鞭子來打它
I beat other dogs with a cane when they're naughty.
#它現在好像又懷孕了
She seems to be pregnant again.
#它的腳現在 上次受像了
Her leg is now...it was injured previously.
#受傷了 現在慢慢快恢復了
It was injured, but it's now recovering gradually.
#你別過來哦 過我我就打你
Don't come! If you do, I'll beat you!
#打你
Beat you!
#再生一窩的話 這就變狗場了
With one more litter, here will become a dog farm.
#全部是狗
All are dogs.
#一地都是狗 一場地都是狗
Dogs are everywhere, all over the site.
#它這毛現在越來越亮了 發亮了
Her hair is getting more and more shiny. It's so shiny.
#你看 它們兩個在打架
Look! The two dogs are having a fight.
#我有好吃的我都優先給它
She is my number one whenever I have any good food.
#其他的都不管它
I just don't care about the others.
#過來 你給我過來
Come here! You come here!
#你們就不要過來啦 你們過來就要舔我
No! You guys don't come to me. You're always licking me.
#不要過來
Don't come!
#你們不要過來 你們一過來就是舔我
Don't come! You just lick me whenever you get close to me.
#哎呦 小狗狗
Ayo! Little puppy!
#這隻狗有點像兄弟那條狗哦
This dog is a bit like my buddy's dog.
#憂鬱的狗
Depressed dog.
#你再憂鬱一點嘛
Hey! Be more depressed!
#這裡上次被那個
It was, I mean,
#大狗跟了一下它 沒事
kicked by the big dogs. But never mind.
#腫了
It was swollen.
#現在好了
But it's fine now.
#敢不敢去啦
Do you dare to go again?
#敢不敢啦
Do you?
#一動不動
It's like a statue.
#握握手
Hand!
#來跳舞
Dance!
#要不要跟你跳拉丁舞
Do you want to have a Latin dance with me?
#它很喜歡跟我玩的這個
It likes playing with me, this,
#這條狗
this puppy.
#幸好這些狗都是和睦相處 不打架
Fortunately, the dogs are getting along well with each other. They don't fight.
#要是打架又頭痛了
It would be a great headache otherwise.
#吃得好飽啊
It has eaten a lot.
#整個肚子都是圓溜溜的
Its stomach is as round as a ball,
#圓滾滾的
almost spherical.
#小狗
Puppy!
#應我一下啊
Answer me!
#生無可戀的樣子
You look so hopeless.
#現在放你下去放你下去
I let you go, let you go now.
#不可以咬它啊
Don't bite!
#咬它我要揍你哦
I'll beat you if you do.
#等下我要揍你
I'll beat you.
#揍你
Beat you.
#你牙齒都掉了 咬我棍子
You're going to lose your teeth if you keep biting my rod.
#好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
#我要去煮飯啦
I need to cook now.